<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rhysnewell</title><link>https://rhysnewell.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on rhysnewell</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rhysnewell.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A collection of logos I went and did.</title><link>https://rhysnewell.github.io/posts/a-collection-of-logos-i-went-and-did/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rhysnewell.github.io/posts/a-collection-of-logos-i-went-and-did/</guid><description>Hello there,
I figured out how to make half-decent logos for the programs and projects I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in. I wanted to make a little gallery to celebrate them, because I think they are kind of cool.
First up, we got the logos that I made for my main projects!
Lorikeet Lorikeet is the project I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the longest time. I love it, and I hate it. Mostly I love it, it does a lot of cool stuff and has changed A LOT over the years.</description></item><item><title>Git Makes Me Feel Like a Git</title><link>https://rhysnewell.github.io/posts/helpful-git-commands/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rhysnewell.github.io/posts/helpful-git-commands/</guid><description>Introduction There are many things in this world that make me truly feel like a fool. One of them is perhaps one of the most useful tools any programmer could use: Git. Which is unfortunate for me, considering I am a programmer&amp;hellip; Sort of.
My understanding of how to properly use Git to its full extent is incredibly lacking. It&amp;rsquo;s like when you &amp;ldquo;learn&amp;rdquo; another language in high school, and then when faced with an actual real world encounter of said language you&amp;rsquo;ve got no idea of what is going on.</description></item><item><title>About Rhys</title><link>https://rhysnewell.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rhysnewell.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hi!
My name is Rhys, and I WAS a PhD candidate at the Centre for Microbiome Research, QUT, Australia. Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for the examination of my thesis to be completed. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;m acting as a software developer and data scientist at CMR focused on the development of improved metagenomic bioinformatic workflows, machine learning applications in microbiology, and diversity analysis algorithms using read assembly techniques. I&amp;rsquo;ve developed an affinity for a number of programming languages including Rust, Python, and R.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://rhysnewell.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rhysnewell.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Follow me, @rhysnewell.
Email me, rhys.newell94@gmail.com</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://rhysnewell.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rhysnewell.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Lorikeet Lorikeet is a variant calling, strain genome resolving, and microdiversity assessment algorithm for metagenomics. The variant calling algorithm Lorikeet uses is a full re-implementation of the GATK HaplotypeCaller algorithm in Rust. It is both faster and easier to use with almost identical results. Lorikeet can make use of both long and short reads simultaneously, handling both the mapping and parallelization of the analysis of multiple genomes with minimal effort required of the user.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://rhysnewell.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rhysnewell.github.io/publications/</guid><description>Published Newell, R. J. P., Pienaar, R., Balderson, B., Piper, M., Essebier, A., &amp;amp; Bodén, M., 2021. ChIP-R: Assembling reproducible sets of ChIP-seq and ATAC-seq peaks from multiple replicates, Genomics, 113(4), pp.1855-1866 Foley, G., Mora, A., Ross, C. M., Bottoms, S., Sützl, L., Lamprecht, M. L., Zaugg, J., Essebier, A., Balderson, B., Newell, R. J. P., Thomson, R. E. S., Kobe, B., Barnard, R. T., Guddat, L., Schenk, G., Carsten, J.</description></item><item><title>Talks &amp; Awards</title><link>https://rhysnewell.github.io/conferences/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rhysnewell.github.io/conferences/</guid><description>Talks &amp;amp; Posters ISOGENIE, Florida State University Marine Lab. Florida, USA, 2019. Oral: Quantifying metabolite abundance with FTICR-MS in Stordalen mire, Abisko, Sweden. GIW/ABACBS &amp;amp; COMBINE/AYRCOB, University of Sydney. Sydney, New South Wales, Australia 2019. Lightning talk &amp;amp; poster: Strain level genotyping of microbial communities using long and short read phasing. EMERGE, Online, 2020. Oral: Strain level genotyping and observation of co-phyletic relationships in two potentially symbiotic bacteria.</description></item></channel></rss>